Total Experience: 3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Notice Period: 1 Month

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E.

[Electronics/Telecommunication]

AL RAPEEK J (1) Featured

Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Engineering, Application Support, Project Management, Change Management, Configuration Management, Cyber Security, Requirement Gathering, Unit Testing, Embedded C, Data Structures, Programming, AUTOSAR, Linux, SVN



Current Designation: Software Engineer

Current Company: BLUE BINARIES ENGINEERING AND

SOLUTION

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Pref. Location: Chennai, Bengaluru / Bangalore, Germany Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Engineer/Developer, Software Engineering, Application Support, Project Management, Change Management, Configuration Management, Cyber Security, Requirement Gathering, Unit Testing, Embedded C, Data

Structures, Programming, AUTOSAR, Linux, SVN

Verified: Phone Number 1 Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

To be part of an organization, which utilizes my skills and expertise in its process of growth, challenges and changes, while giving me ample opportunity to learn and enrich my competencies, to make meaningful and substantial contribution

Work Experience

BLUE BINARIES ENGINEERING AND SOLUTION as Software Engineer

Jun 2020 to Till Date

- Experienced in AUTOSAR stack configuration using Vector Davinci configurator and Developer
- Strong knowledge on c programming language
- ? Hands on experience on AUTOSAR architecture.
- Good understanding on UDS (ISO-14229) and CAN protocol.
- ? Build and Integration of AUTOSAR CAN and Diagnostic stack
- ? Handson experience in debugging using Debugger like UDE.
- Bootloader Diagnostics, Programming.
- Good knowledge on SDLC phases.
- Good knowledge in communication protocols like CAN, UART, SPI.
- Experience in Unit testing and integration testing of the software

L&T Technology and Service as Software Engineer

Feb 2018 to May 2020

Project Name

AUTOSAR-PODS Duration Feb 2018 to

May 2020

Team Size 15

Designed to classify the occupant seated in front passenger seat for potential airbag suppression, PODS classify the seat as empty or the occupant as an adult or infant/child. The system converts pressure inside a fluid filled

bladder into an occupant classification, providing three state occupant classification capability empty, child and adult.

Role & Contribution

- Understanding of customer requirements for Application Service Utility modules related to Cybersecurity.
- Understanding of cybersecurity from high level architecture for finding vulnerabilities (eg: through instruction destruction mechanism).
- Design of SSC(Security Service Coordinator), ERRH(Error Handler), SUSD(App Startup, shutdown), SSM(Signal Service Monitoring) software components to support crypto SUM component.
- Creation of Component diagram and Class diagram using Enterprise Architect.
- Design and development of the source code for some of the runnables.
- SWC and RTE mapping using Davinci developer and configurator.
- Configuration of other crypto dependent modules like DEM, DCM, CAN, CAN IF, CAN TP, PDUR, COM, using Davinci configurator tool.
- Worked on Implementation of vehicle diagnostic services based on the ISO 14229-1(UDS) and ISO 157652 (CAN-UDS) as per the requirement from the Customer by using Davinci tools.
- Execution of functional testing and Integration Testing in the bench set up by using CanOe.
- Final integration of the software into the desired module and delivery of software to the customer.

Preparation of Calibration document for SUM module.

Debug and fix the issues while testing.

Testing of CAN and UDS services on the hardware.

Discussion of the issues in daily standup meetings.

Quality and ontime delivery of the software

Review and ensure the working of the software.

Project Name

AUTOSAR- Bootloader configuration and Integration

Duration 1 years Team Size

Description The scope of project is to configure and integrate Vector Bootloader Stack. The ECU is based on RH850 HW platform. The project activities include BSW configuration using Vector Davinci configurator

Role and contribution * Board bring up Renesas RH850 controller

- Configuration of BSW modules like DEM, DCM, CAN, CAN IF, CAN TP, PDUR, COM, using Davinci configurator tool.
- Configuration of DIDs, RIDs, DTCs using DEM and DCM.
- Configuration of SIDs \$34, \$36 and \$37 in DCM.
- Implemented software local rollback functionality in Bootloader.
- Integration Testing of Re-programming sequence using DPS programming tool

Technologies Embedded C

Microcontroller RH850

Tools Davinci Configurator, Enterprise Architect, Doors, DPS Programming tool, GreenHills compiler.

Project 3:

Project Name

IMAGE SETGANOGRAPHY Duration 1month

Team Size

The art and science of hiding information by embedding messages within other, seemingly harmless messages. Bits of unused data are replaced by bits of valuable information.

Role and contribution The use of file pointers and File operators.

- Byte wise and bitwise manipulation of data by declaring a local buffer to encrypt and decrypt data.
- The use and implementation of Make files.

Technologies Embedded C

C-language-Function pointer, Bitwise operations, String operations, File I/O operations, File operations

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Sri krishna college of technology in coimbatore in 2016

IT Skills

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=979a5e01d3ac6c141e31a4592a13d35f5e5d01591f150b405747495e5c...

	Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
-	Embedded C, Data Structures, Linux			
	Windows 7, SVN, EA, DOORS, RFP			
	RENESAS RH850, Visual Studio code			

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Tamil				
German				
Deutsche				

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary

Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time